<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<NamingSystem xmlns="http://hl7.org/fhir">
  <id value="ADAUniversalToothDesignationSystem"/>
  <extension url="http://hl7.org/fhir/5.0/StructureDefinition/extension-NamingSystem.title">
    <valueString value="ADA Universal Tooth Designation System"/>
  </extension>
  <extension url="http://hl7.org/fhir/5.0/StructureDefinition/extension-NamingSystem.url">
    <valueUri value="http://terminology.hl7.org/NamingSystem/ADAUniversalToothDesignationSystem"/>
  </extension>
  <extension url="http://terminology.hl7.org/StructureDefinition/ext-namingsystem-version">
    <valueString value="1.0.0"/>
  </extension>
  <name value="ADAUniversalToothDesignationSystem"/>
  <status value="active"/>
  <kind value="codesystem"/>
  <date value="2022-04-07T00:00:00-00:00"/>
  <publisher value="American Dental Association"/>
  <contact>
    <name value="American Dental Association; 211 East Chicago Avenue Chicago, IL 60610-2678"/>
  </contact>
  <description value="The American Dental Association (ADA) accepted the Universal/National Tooth Designation System and the ISO/ANSI/ADA Specification No. 3950 for Designation System for Teeth and Areas of the Oral Cavity as the human tooth and oral cavity enumeration schemas in 1994.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;The universal tooth designation or numbering system is accepted and approved by the ADA and is the most commonly used system used by dental professionals in America.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Teeth are numbered 1-32, starting with the third molar (1) on the right side of the upper arch, following around the arch to the third molar (16) on the left side, and descending to the lower third molar (17) on the left side, and following that arch to the terminus of the lower jaw, the lower right third molar (32).&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Supernumerary teeth are identified by the numbers 51 through 82, beginning with the area of the upper right third molar, following around the upper arch and continuing on the lower arch to the area of the lower right third molar (e.g., supernumerary &#35;51 is adjacent to the upper right molar &#35;1; supernumerary &#35;82 is adjacent to the lower right third molar &#35;32).&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;The Universal Numbering System can be found in the ADA Dental Claim Form. For more information see here: https://www.ada.org/publications/cdt/ada-dental-claim-form. &#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;A Statement of Understanding (SOU) between ADA and HL7 exists here: http://www.hl7.org/documentcenter/public/mou/ADA%20HL7%20SOU%202021_signed.pdf"/>
  <uniqueId>
    <type value="uri"/>
    <value value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/ADAUniversalToothDesignationSystem"/>
    <preferred value="true"/>
	<comment value="This is the URL endorsed by the HTA and is considered authoritative."/>
	<period>
      <start value="2022-04-07"/>
    </period>
  </uniqueId>
</NamingSystem>