<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<NamingSystem xmlns="http://hl7.org/fhir">
  <id value="ICFDut"/>
  <title value="International Classification of Functioning, Disability and Health, Dutch Translation"/>
  <url value="http://terminology.hl7.org/NamingSystem/ICFDut"/>
  <version value="1.0.0"/>
  <name value="ICFDut"/>
  <status value="active"/>
  <kind value="codesystem"/>
  <date value="2022-10-11T00:00:00-00:00"/>
  <publisher value="WHO Collaborating Center for the Family of International Classifications (FIC) in the Netherlands"/>
  <contact>
    <name value="WHO Collaborating Center for the Family of International Classifications (FIC) in the Netherlands"/>
	<telecom>
		<system value="url"/>
		<value value="https://www.whofic.nl/over-het-centrum"/>
	</telecom>
  </contact>
  <responsible value="WHO Collaborating Center for the Family of International Classifications (FIC) in the Netherlands"/>
  <description value="&quot;The International Classification of Functioning, Disability and Health, known more commonly as ICF, is a classification of health and health-related domains.
As the functioning and disability of an individual occurs in a context, ICF also includes a list of environmental factors.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;ICF is the WHO framework for measuring health and disability at both individual and population levels.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;ICF was officially endorsed by all 191 WHO Member States in the Fifty-fourth World Health Assembly on 22 May 2001(resolution [WHA 54.21](http://apps.who.int/gb/archive/pdf_files/WHA54/ea54r21.pdf) ) as the international standard to describe and measure health and disability.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;ICF is based on the same foundation as ICD and ICHI and share the same set of extension codes that enable documentation at a higher level of detail.&quot;&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;&quot;The Dutch translation of the ICF is published in book form by BSL. The ICF can also be consulted online in the [Classification Browser](https://class.whofic.nl/browser.aspx?scheme=ICF-nl.cla).&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;The ICF team of the WHO-FIC Collaborating Center combines expertise in the field of the ICF for the Dutch language area and currently consists of delegations from the Netherlands Paramedical Institute, the University Medical Center Groningen, Maastricht University, the Big Move Institute, Stichting Scientific Research Road Safety, University of Ghent, Vilans, and Rehabilitation Center de Hoogstraat.&quot;&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Official updates to the ICF are available as annual lists of changes.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;These updates are approved annually at the October meeting of the WHO Family of International Classifications (WHO-FIC) Network.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;To license ICF, the same rules apply for ICF as for ICD. See [http://icd.who.int/](http://icd.who.int/).&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;For more information, see [https://www.whofic.nl/familie-van-internationale-classificaties/referentie-classificaties/icf](https://www.whofic.nl/familie-van-internationale-classificaties/referentie-classificaties/icf)."/>
  <uniqueId>
    <type value="uri"/>
    <value value="http://hl7.org/fhir/sid/icf-nl"/>
    <preferred value="true"/>
	<comment value="This is the URL as specified by the terminology owner, and is considered authoritative."/>
	<period>
      <start value="2022-10-13"/>
    </period>
  </uniqueId>
</NamingSystem>