<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<NamingSystem xmlns="http://hl7.org/fhir">
  <id value="NCPDPFormularyStatus"/>
  <title value="NCPDP Formulary Status"/>
  <url value="http://terminology.hl7.org/NamingSystem/NCPDPFormularyStatus"/>
  <version value="20260409"/>
  <name value="NCPDP Formulary Status"/>
  <status value="active"/>
  <kind value="codesystem"/>
  <date value="2026-04-09T00:00:00-04:00"/>
  <publisher value="National Council for Prescription Drug Programs (NCPDP)"/>
  <contact>
    <name value="National Council for Prescription Drug Programs (NCPDP)"/>
    <telecom>
		<system value="url"/>
		<value value="https://www.ncpdp.org/"/>
	</telecom>
  </contact>
  <responsible value="National Council for Prescription Drug Programs (NCPDP)"/>
  <description value="An NCPDP-defined code that indicates the status of a drug within a formulary (NCPDP ECL 927-FP). See [https://standards.ncpdp.org/Access-to-Standards.asp](https://standards.ncpdp.org/Access-to-Standards.asp) for more information (Only NCPDP members can view documentation)."/>
  <copyright value="&quot;National Council for Prescription Drugs Programs, Inc. (NCPDP) publications are owned by NCPDP, 9240 East Raintree Drive Scottsdale, AZ 85260, and protected by the copyright laws of the United States and other countries. 17 U.S.C. §101, et. seq.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Subject to the restrictions described below, NCPDP grants permission to NCPDP members to copy and use NCPDP publications in connection with the business purposes of the Council members solely in support of healthcare transactions conducted wholly within the United States. The NCPDP publications may not be changed or altered. The NCPDP publications may be shared with employees within the member company with a reasonable need to know but may not be (1) disclosed or distributed to any unauthorized party or (2) used without NCPDP's express written permission outside the United States. The NCPDP publications may not be disclosed, copied, modified, compiled, sold, used, published, or exploited for commercial purposes except as expressly authorized herein. This permission may be revoked by NCPDP at any time. NCPDP is not responsible for any errors or damage in any way associated with the use of NCPDP publications. Except as expressly permitted herein, NCPDP publications may not be provided to third parties without NCPDP's express written authorization, and members and other recipients of NCPDP publications must not, directly or indirectly, (1) publish or participate in the publication, sharing, or disclosure of any NCPDP publication to any third party, or (2) authorize, permit, or encourage any third party to do so. Any such member or other recipient of an NCPDP publication waives all rights to share NCPDP publications, including any right based on “fair use,” and will be responsible for any and all such disclosures, including but not limited to disclosures by employees, agents, contractors, affiliates, or other third parties acting on behalf of or with the knowledge or consent of such member or other recipient.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;All NCPDP publications and other material are provided &quot;as is&quot;, without warranty of any kind, express or implied, including but not limited to warranties of merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose, accuracy, completeness, and non-infringement of third-party rights. In no event shall NCPDP, its members, or its contributors be liable for any claim, or any direct, special, indirect, or consequential damages, or any damages whatsoever resulting from loss of use, data, or profits, whether in an action of contract, negligence, or other tortious action, arising out of or in connection with the use or performance of NCPDP publications or other NCPDP material.&quot;&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;See [https://www.ncpdp.org/NCPDP/media/pdf/Bylaws.pdf](https://www.ncpdp.org/NCPDP/media/pdf/Bylaws.pdf).&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;* Sharing data that contains values from NCPDP code sets isn't prohibited by the copyright. But sharing or publishing a full NCPDP code set and definitions is.&#13;&#10;* A party may share data containing NCPDP codes with a receiver that isn't an NCPDP member.&#13;&#10;* A party that isn't an NCPDP member may capture and later share data containing NCPDP codes with another party. Both the sending and receiving parties would be limited in their ability to understand and validate the information if they don't have access to the full code systems."/>
  <uniqueId>
    <type value="uri"/>
    <value value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/NCPDPFormularyStatus"/>
    <preferred value="true"/>
    <comment value="This is the official URI endorsed by the TSMG for use in HL7 standards."/>
  </uniqueId>
</NamingSystem>