<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/r5/fhir-single.xsd">
  <ul class="nav nav-tabs">
    <li><a href="codesystems.html">All Code Systems</a></li>
    <li><a href="codesystems-cda.html">CDA</a></li>
    <li><a href="codesystems-fhir.html">FHIR</a></li>
    <li><a href="codesystems-v2.html">V2</a></li>
    <li><a href="codesystems-v3.html">V3</a></li>
    <li><a href="codesystems-unified.html">Unified</a></li>
    <li class="active"><a href="#">External</a></li>
    <li><a href="codesystems-retired.html">Retired</a></li>
  </ul>
  <p>
    This page lists the code systems that are curated and published by organizations other than HL7.  In a few of these, HL7 has signed agreements for redistribution of non-HL7 published content 
    from the owners of the terminology.  For these External Code systems, content that is needed in HL7 published artifacts is contained here in UTG CodeSystem resources (based on 
    FHIR CodeSystem resource specifications), however note that in nearly all cases these CodeSystem resources contain only a subset of the external code system content - only the 
    portion that is explicity used and referenced in HL7 published artifacts.  The full content is available from the listed publisher of the code systems. 
  </p>
  <p>
    HL7 specification using content on these pages contains and references intellectual property owned by third parties ("Third Party IP").  Implementers and testers of these specifications SHALL abide by the license requirements for each terminology content artifact utilized within a functioning implementation. Terminology licenses SHALL be obtained from the Third Party IP owner for each code system and/or other specified artifact used. It is the sole responsibility of each organization deploying or testing this specification to ensure their implementations comply with licensing requirements of each Third Party IP.
    HL7 has secured agreements governing access to and the use of some of these terminologies for the convenience of the HL7 community.

  </p>
  <p>
    The vast majority of the entries listed below however have no coded content; the entries exist here for convenient access by the HL7 Community to the identifiers of the code systems (OIDs, URIs, etc.) and 
    and some contact information to locate the owner for access to the content, thus enabling the securing of the content and the rights to use it.  A number of these also have descriptions that the HL7 Community has found helpful over the years.   Recommendations 
    on the use of the terminologies where HL7 has agreements, and for using these terminologies in general, may be found on the <a href="http://www.hl7.org/about/agreements.cfm?ref=nav">HL7 Agreements page</a>. 
  </p>
  <ul class="columns-3">
    {% include List-external-Rendering-list-name-simple-CodeSystem.xhtml %}
  </ul>
</div>