<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/r5/fhir-single.xsd">
  <ul class="nav nav-tabs">
    <li><a href="codesystems.html">All Code Systems</a></li>
    <li><a href="codesystems-cda.html">CDA</a></li>
    <li><a href="codesystems-fhir.html">FHIR</a></li>
    <li class="active"><a href="#">V2</a></li>
    <li><a href="codesystems-v3.html">V3</a></li>
    <li><a href="codesystems-unified.html">Unified</a>
    </li><li><a href="codesystems-external.html">External</a></li>
    <li><a href="codesystems-retired.html">Retired</a></li>
  </ul>
  <p>
    These pages contain the code systems defined by HL7, and published in the Version 2 International Standards for use in the V2 product family.
  </p>
  <p>
    Historically, the Version 2 terminology content was expressed in a legacy vocabulary model - Tables.   In the evolution to a more modern and unified representation of terminology, 
    all of the published content of these Version 2 Tables is now represented as Code Systems and Value Sets.  The tables themselves, with their table-specific metadata, are here represented as concepts in the code system 
    "V2Tables", which may be browsed below. The meta-data of each individual V2 table contains textual and usage information, and references to the code systems and value sets providing the codes 
    for each Table; this may be viewed in the concept properties in the V2Tables code system. 
  </p>
  <p>
    All of this content has previousy been published in the HL7 Version 2 Standard, Chapter 2C Code Tables.  This Code Tables chapter contains the code tables originally documented in individual 
    chapters of the HL7 Version 2 Standard.  As of HL7 Version 2.7, a proposal was accepted to move all of the tables to a common document.  This separation allows these artifacts, which are often 
    subject to more frequent change to meet regulatory requirements than the typical release cycles of ANSI Standards publication, to be available on a more responsive schedule than the rest of the standard. 
  </p>
  <p>
    This representation of the Version 2 coded content in code systems and value set will support use in, and harmonization with, the HL7 Implementation Guides and Standards published in HL7 FHIR, HL7 Version 3, and the HL7 Clinical Document Architecture. 
  </p>
  <ul class="columns-3">
    {% include List-v2-rendering-list-name-simple-CodeSystem.xhtml %}
  </ul>
</div>
