<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/r5/fhir-single.xsd">
  <ul class="nav nav-tabs">
    <li><a href="codesystems.html">All Code Systems</a></li>
    <li><a href="codesystems-cda.html">CDA</a></li>
    <li><a href="codesystems-fhir.html">FHIR</a></li>
    <li><a href="codesystems-v2.html">V2</a></li>
    <li><a href="codesystems-v3.html">V3</a></li>
    <li><a href="codesystems-unified.html">Unified</a></li>
    <li class="active"><a href="#">External</a></li>
    <li><a href="codesystems-retired.html">Retired</a></li>
  </ul>
  <p>
    This page lists the code systems that are curated and published by organizations other than HL7.  In a few of these, HL7 has signed agreements for redistribution of non-HL7 published content 
    from the owners of the terminology.  For these External Code systems, content that is needed in HL7 published artifacts is contained here in UTG CodeSystem resources (based on 
    FHIR CodeSystem resource specifications), however note that in nearly all cases these CodeSystem resources contain only a subset of the external code system content - only the 
    portion that is explicity used and referenced in HL7 published artifacts.  The full content is available from the listed publisher of the code systems. 
  </p>
  <p>
    The vast majority of these entries have no coded content; the entries exist here for convenient access by the HL7 Community to the identifiers of the code systems (OIDs, URIs, etc.) and 
    and some contact information to locate the owner for access to the content.  A number of these also have descriptions that the HL7 Community has found helpful over the years.   Recommendations 
    on the use of some of these in HL7 artifacts, and for using these terminologies in general, may be found on the <a href="https://confluence.hl7.org/display/TA/External+Terminologies+-+Information">
    External Terminologies information pages</a> maintained by the HL7 Terminology Authority.
  </p>
  <ul class="columns-3">
    {% include List-external-Rendering-list-name-simple-CodeSystem.xhtml %}
  </ul>
</div>