<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/r5/fhir-single.xsd">
  <ul class="nav nav-tabs">
    <li class="active"><a href="#">All Content</a></li>
    <li><a href="external_terminologies_csmr.html">Code System Metadata Records</a></li>
    <li><a href="external_terminologies_csti.html">Code System Identification</a></li>
    <li><a href="external_terminologies_csf.html">Code System Fragments</a></li>
    <li><a href="external_terminologies_ccs.html">Complete Code Systems</a></li>
    <li><a href="external_terminologies_rc.html">Retired Content</a></li>
  </ul>
  <p>
    External terminologies information defined by HL7 and published in HL7 International Standards
  </p>
  <p>
    The list of external systems here consists of two types of systems maintained by HL7 through the Unified Terminology Governance (UTG) process, 
    and published by HL7 in the different HL7 product families.  Currently these are information and history tracking for changed primary 
    technical identifiers (URIs and OIDs) for External Code Systems (published by organizations outside of HL7), and Pending Code 
    Systems, ie defined planned URIs and names that will be created in THO soon but are not yet present. The information captured 
    in these resources is persisted and rendered here from underlying NamingSystem resources.
    Updates and maintenace in UTG is a continuous process, and the content available here is updated frequently.
  </p>
  <p>
    The resources that are defined here are for the convenience of HL7 implementers.  These naming system resources serve the 
    special purpose of capturing for easy access multiple different identifiers for Code Systems that have been used in the past, as well as those that are currently preferred. 
    THey are made available here for those that are looking for identifiers that may have been published in the past in HL7 Standards, 
    but have been superceded since that time.  
  </p>

  <!-- Code System Metadata Records -->
  <p>
  <b>Code System Metadata Records</b><br/>
  <i>HTA Curated Code System Metadata Records</i>
  <ul class="columns-3">
    {% include List-extcsmetadatarecords-Rendering-list-name-simple-CodeSystem.xhtml %}
  </ul>
  <i>Other Code System Metadata Records</i>
  <ul class="columns-3">
    {% include List-external-Rendering-list-name-simple-CodeSystem.xhtml %}
  </ul>
  </p>

  <!-- Code System Technical Identifiers -->
  <p>
  <b>Code System Technical Identifiers</b><br/>
  <i>HTA Currated Technical Tdentifiers</i>
  <ul class="columns-3">
    {% include List-techids-Rendering-list-id-simple-NamingSystem.xhtml %}
  </ul>
  <i>Other Technical Identifiers</i>
  <ul class="columns-3">
    {% include List-techidsoth-Rendering-list-id-simple-NamingSystem.xhtml %}
  </ul>
  </p>
  
  <!-- Code System Fragments -->
  <p>
  <b>Code System Fragments</b>
  <ul class="columns-3">
    {% include List-extwcontent-Rendering-list-name-simple-CodeSystem.xhtml %}
  </ul>
  </p>

  <!-- Complete Code Systems-->
  <p>
  <b>Complete Code Systems</b>
  <ul class="columns-3">
    <li>None</li>
  </ul>
  </p>
  </div>