<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/r5/fhir-single.xsd">
  <ul class="nav nav-tabs">
    <li><a href="external_terminologies.html">All Content</a></li>
    <li><a href="external_terminologies_csmr.html">Code System Metadata Records</a></li>
    <li class="active"><a href="#">Code System Technical Identifiers</a></li>
    <li><a href="external_terminologies_csf.html">Code System Fragments</a></li>
    <li><a href="external_terminologies_ccs.html">Complete Code Systems</a></li>
    <li><a href="external_terminologies_rc.html">Retired Content</a></li>
  </ul>
  <p>
    These pages contain the metadata and tracking information for code systems published in the HL7 Terminology pages.
  </p>
  <p>
    The content here consists information and history tracking for changed primary 
    technical identifiers (URIs and OIDs and others) for Code Systems, and   
    is persisted and rendered from underlying NamingSystem resources.  These identifiers are used in data elements of 
    coded data types in the various HL7 product families.
  </p>
  <a name="HTA_Curated_Technical_Identifiers"/>
  <b>HTA Curated Technical Identifiers</b>
  <p>
    The <a href="http://www.hl7.org/Special/committees/termauth/overview.cfm">HL7 Terminology Authority (HTA)</a> is 
    responsible for the creation, implementation, and management of HL7 processes involving external terminology management.
    One of these processes is to liaise with the owners, stewards and publishers of external terminologies to obtain accurate
    business and technical metadata about the terminology for use in HL7 standards. Technical identifiers (e.g. code system URI
    or OID identifiers) for these terminologies are then published in HL7 Terminology and curated by the HTA. Changes to these
    records are strictly based on decisions of the HTA. However, stakeholders may submit change requests to the HTA for consideration.
  </p>
  <ul class="columns-3">
    {% include List-techids-Rendering-list-id-simple-NamingSystem.xhtml %}
  </ul>
  <b>Other Technical Identifiers</b>
  <p>
    Additional technical identifiers that have been published at some time in the past (usually in HL7 V2 or HL7 V3 Standards) have been 
    imported here for reference.   At the current time, these have not yet been reviewed or placed under HTA curation (list above), and 
    solely represent what may have been published in the past.  All of these are subject to review and either correction, amendment, or 
    even removal.   
  </p>
  <ul class="columns-3">
    {% include List-techidsoth-Rendering-list-id-simple-NamingSystem.xhtml %}
  </ul>
</div>
