<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/r5/fhir-single.xsd">
  <ul class="nav nav-tabs">
    <li><a href="external_terminologies.html">All Content</a></li>
    <li class="active"><a href="#">Code System Metadata Records</a></li>
    <li><a href="external_terminologies_csti.html">Code System Identification</a></li>
    <li><a href="external_terminologies_csf.html">Code System Fragments</a></li>
    <li><a href="external_terminologies_ccs.html">Complete Code Systems</a></li>
    <li><a href="external_terminologies_rc.html">Retired Content</a></li>
  </ul>
  <p>
    These pages contain HL7's recorded metadata information for external terminologies which is published in the HL7 
    Terminology pages. These are not the actual code system instances, they are only noted information about these 
    code systems (sometimes referred to as 'stubs').
  </p>
  <p>
    The lists of content here is maintained by HL7 through the Unified Terminology Governance (UTG) process, and is 
    published by HL7 in the different HL7 product families. Updates and and maintenance in UTG is a continuous process, 
    and the content available here is updated frequently. 
  </p>
  <a name="Code_System_Metadata_Records"/>
  <b>Code System Metadata Records</b>
  <p>
    The <a href="http://www.hl7.org/Special/committees/termauth/overview.cfm">HL7 Terminology Authority (HTA)</a> is 
    responsible for the creation, implementation, and management of HL7 processes involving external terminology management.
    One of these processes is to liaise with the owners, stewards and publishers of external terminologies to obtain accurate
    business and technical metadata about the terminology for use in HL7 standards. This information is then published in these
    metadata records in HL7 Terminology and curated by the HTA. Changes to these records are strictly based on decisions of the HTA.
    However, stakeholders may submit change requests to the HTA for consideration.
  </p>
  <ul class="columns-3">
    {% include List-extcsmetadatarecords-Rendering-list-name-simple-CodeSystem.xhtml %}
  </ul>
</div>
