<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<NamingSystem xmlns="http://hl7.org/fhir">
  <id value="v3-medcin"/>
  <extension url="http://terminology.hl7.org/StructureDefinition/ext-namingsystem-title">
    <valueString value="MEDCIN"/>
  </extension>
  <extension url="http://terminology.hl7.org/StructureDefinition/ext-namingsystem-version">
    <valueString value="2.0.0"/>
  </extension>
  <name value="Medcin"/>
  <url value="http://terminology.hl7.org/NamingSystem/v3-medcin"/>
  <status value="active"/>
  <kind value="codesystem"/>
  <date value="2019-03-20T00:00:00-04:00"/>
  <publisher value="Medicomp Systems"/>
  <contact>
    <name value="David Lareau"/>
  </contact>
  <responsible value="Medicomp Systems"/>
  <description value="MEDCIN contains more than 175,000 clinical data elements arranged in a hierarchy, with each item having weighted links to relevant diagnoses. The clinical data elements are organized into six basic termtypes designed to accommodate information relevant to a clinical encounter. The basic termtypes in MEDCIN&#39;s terminological hierarchy are as follows:&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Symptoms History Physical Examination Tests Diagnoses Therapy&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Within this basic structure, MEDCIN terms are further organized in a ten level terminological hierarchy, supplemented by an optional, multi-hierarchical diagnostic index. For example, the symptom of &quot;difficulty breathing&quot; is placed in the terminological hierarchy as a subsidiary (or &quot;child&quot;) finding of &quot;pulmonary symptoms,&quot; although the presence (or absence) of difficulty breathing can related to conditions as diverse as myocardial infarction, bronchitis, pharyngeal foreign bodies, asthma, pulmonary embolism, etc. MEDCIN&#39;s diagnostic index provides more than 800 such links for difficulty breathing."/>
  <uniqueId>
    <type value="oid"/>
    <value value="2.16.840.1.113883.6.26"/>
    <preferred value="true"/>
  </uniqueId>
  <uniqueId>
    <type value="uri"/>
    <value value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-medcin"/>
    <preferred value="true"/>
  </uniqueId>
</NamingSystem>