<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<ValueSet xmlns="http://hl7.org/fhir">
  <id value="v3-ActClassExposure"/>
  <language value="en"/>
  <text>
    <status value="generated"/>
    <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                  
      <p>The action of coming into sufficient physical proximity to allow physical or chemical interaction.  Examples include: exposure to radiation, inhalation of peanut aerosol or viral particles.  This includes intended exposure (e.g. administering a drug product) as well as accidental or environmental exposure.  Actual vs. potential exposure can be differentiated using Act.uncertaintyCode.</p>
                  
      <p>The agent to which the subject was exposed is conveyed as a 
        <i>Direct</i> participation or specialization there-of.
      </p>
                  
      <p>
                     
        <i>Constraints:</i>  The following Participations should be used with the following Roles and Entities to distinguish the specific entities:
      </p>
                  
      <ul>
                     
        <li>
                        
          <p>The 
            <b>
                              
              <i>exposed entity</i>
                           
            </b> is the entity of interest that is the recipient of the exposure and potentially affected.  This is conveyed through the subject (SBJ) Participation. 
          </p>
                     
        </li>
                     
        <li>
                        
          <p>An entity that has carried the agent transmitted in the exposure is the &quot;
            <b>
                              
              <i>exposure source</i>
                           
            </b>&quot; (EXSRC).  For example: 
          </p>
                        
          <ul>
                           
            <li>
                              
              <p>a person or animal who carried an infectious disease and interacts (EXSRC) with another person or animal (SBJ) transmitting the disease agent; or </p>
                           
            </li>
                           
            <li>
                              
              <p>a place or other environment (EXSRC) and a person or animal (SBJ) who is exposed in the presence of this environment.</p>
                           
            </li>
                        
          </ul>
                     
        </li>
                     
        <li>
                        
          <p>When it is unknown whether a participating entity is the source of the agent (EXSRC) or the target of the transmission (SBJ), also known as &quot;
            <b>
                              
              <i>exposure contact</i>
                           
            </b>&quot;, the &quot;participant&quot; (PART) is used.
          </p>
                     
        </li>
                     
        <li>
                        
          <p>The substance to which the subject is exposed that carries the exposure agent or the chemical substance of interest itself, participates as a &quot;consumable&quot; (CSM).  There are at least two configurations: (a) the player of the Role that participates as CSM is the chemical or biological substance mixed or carried by the scoper-entity of the Role (e.g., ingredient role); or (b) the player of the Role that participates as CSM is a mixture known to contain the chemical, radiological or biological substance of interest. </p>
                     
        </li>
                     
        <li>
                        
          <p>The device specifically used to administer the substance is associated using the device (DEV) Participation.  This may be a device intentionally used (such as applicator device) or it may be a thing that accidentally carried this substance; for instance, an infected needle or knife.  The same entity may be related in the act as both EXSRC and DEV.</p>
                     
        </li>
                  
      </ul>
               
    </div>
  </text>
  <extension url="http://hl7.org/fhir/StructureDefinition/resource-history">
    <extension url="author">
      <valueString value="Vocabulary (Woody Beeler)"/>
    </extension>
    <extension url="substantiative">
      <valueBoolean value="true"/>
    </extension>
    <extension url="notes">
      <valueString value="Lock all vaue sets untouched since 2014-03-26 to trackingId 2014T1_2014_03_26"/>
    </extension>
  </extension>
  <url value="http://terminology.hl7.org/ValueSet/v3-ActClassExposure"/>
  <identifier>
    <system value="urn:ietf:rfc:3986"/>
    <value value="urn:oid:2.16.840.1.113883.1.11.19832"/>
  </identifier>
  <version value="2014T1_2014-03-26_001283"/>
  <name value="ActClassExposure"/>
  <title value="ActClassExposure"/>
  <status value="active"/>
  <date value="2014-03-26"/>
  <description value=" The action of coming into sufficient physical proximity to allow physical or chemical interaction.  Examples include: exposure to radiation, inhalation of peanut aerosol or viral particles.  This includes intended exposure (e.g. administering a drug product) as well as accidental or environmental exposure.  Actual vs. potential exposure can be differentiated using Act.uncertaintyCode. The agent to which the subject was exposed is conveyed as a&#xD;&#xA; Directparticipation or specialization there-of.  &#xD;&#xA; Constraints:The following Participations should be used with the following Roles and Entities to distinguish the specific entities:   The&#xD;&#xA;  exposed entityis the entity of interest that is the recipient of the exposure and potentially affected.  This is conveyed through the subject (SBJ) Participation.  An entity that has carried the agent transmitted in the exposure is the &quot;&#xD;&#xA;  exposure source&quot; (EXSRC).  For example:   a person or animal who carried an infectious disease and interacts (EXSRC) with another person or animal (SBJ) transmitting the disease agent; or  a place or other environment (EXSRC) and a person or animal (SBJ) who is exposed in the presence of this environment.  When it is unknown whether a participating entity is the source of the agent (EXSRC) or the target of the transmission (SBJ), also known as &quot;&#xD;&#xA;  exposure contact&quot;, the &quot;participant&quot; (PART) is used.  The substance to which the subject is exposed that carries the exposure agent or the chemical substance of interest itself, participates as a &quot;consumable&quot; (CSM).  There are at least two configurations: (a) the player of the Role that participates as CSM is the chemical or biological substance mixed or carried by the scoper-entity of the Role (e.g., ingredient role); or (b) the player of the Role that participates as CSM is a mixture known to contain the chemical, radiological or biological substance of interest.  The device specifically used to administer the substance is associated using the device (DEV) Participation.  This may be a device intentionally used (such as applicator device) or it may be a thing that accidentally carried this substance; for instance, an infected needle or knife.  The same entity may be related in the act as both EXSRC and DEV."/>
  <immutable value="true"/>
  <compose>
    <include>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActClass"/>
      <filter>
        <property value="concept"/>
        <op value="is-a"/>
        <value value="EXPOS"/>
      </filter>
    </include>
  </compose>
</ValueSet>