<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<CodeSystem xmlns="http://hl7.org/fhir">
  <id value="ca-hc-dpd-schedule"/>
  <url value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/ca-hc-dpd-schedule"/>
  <identifier>
    <system value="urn:ietf:rfc:3986"/>
    <value value="urn:oid:2.16.840.1.113883.5.1151"/>
  </identifier>
  <version value="1.0.0"/>
  <name value="Health_Canada_DPD_Schedule"/>
  <title value="Health Canada Drug Product Database - Schedule"/>
  <status value="active"/>
  <experimental value="false"/>
  <date value="2024-11-04T00:00:00-00:00"/>
  <publisher value="Health Canada, Health Products and Food Branch"/>
  <contact>
    <name value="Health Canada; Health Products and Food Branch; Address Locator 1801B, Ottawa, Ontario, K1A 0K9"/>
	<telecom>
		<system value="url"/>
		<value value="https://www.canada.ca/en/health-canada/services/drugs-health-products/drug-products/drug-product-database.html"/>
	</telecom>
	<telecom>
		<system value="email"/>
		<value value="pharma_drug_enquiries-renseignements_medicaments_pharma@hc-sc.gc.ca"/>
	</telecom>
    <telecom>
		<system value="phone"/>
		<value value="1-613-957-2991"/>
	</telecom>
  </contact>
  <description value="The Code System describes the characteristics of drugs for use in Canada.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Drugs in Canada are assigned one or more of the following schedules, according to the Food and Drug Regulations, and the Controlled Drugs and Substances Act.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;- Prescription (prescription drugs included in the Prescription Drug List)&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;- Prescription Recommended (drugs that are recommended to be listed on the Prescription Drug List)&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;- Schedule G (control drugs)&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;- Schedule G (Controlled Drugs and Substances Act [CDSA] III)&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;- Schedule G (CDSA IV)&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;- Schedule C (drugs listed in Schedule C of the Food and Drugs Act, for example, radiopharmaceutical drugs)&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;- Schedule D (drugs listed in Schedule D of the Food and Drugs Act, ie. biological products)&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;- Narcotic (Narcotic Control Act)&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;- Narcotic (CDSA I)&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;- Narcotic (CDSA II)&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;- Targeted (CDSA IV)&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;- CDSA Recommended- Undergoing Regulatory Amendment to add this new substance to Controlled Drugs Substances Act&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;- OTC (over the counter drugs that do not appear on a schedule or are not recommended to appear on any schedule)&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;- Ethical: a drug that, in accordance with Federal Legislation, does not require a prescription, but that is generally prescribed by a medical practitioner. Ethical products are unscheduled non-prescription professional use products (e.g. MRI contrast agents, hemodialysis solutions) and a few emergency use products (e.g. nitroglycerine)"/>
  <caseSensitive value="false"/>
  <content value="not-present"/>
</CodeSystem>