<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<ValueSet xmlns="http://hl7.org/fhir">
  <id value="v3-PhysicalTherapistHIPAA"/>
  <language value="en"/>
  <url value="http://terminology.hl7.org/ValueSet/v3-PhysicalTherapistHIPAA"/>
  <identifier>
    <system value="urn:ietf:rfc:3986"/>
    <value value="urn:oid:2.16.840.1.113883.1.11.13609"/>
  </identifier>
  <version value="2.0.0"/>
  <name value="PhysicalTherapistHIPAA"/>
  <title value="PhysicalTherapistHIPAA"/>
  <status value="retired"/>
  <date value="2014-03-26"/>
  <description value="(1) Physical therapists are health care professionals who evaluate and treat people with health problems resulting from injury or disease. PT&#39;s assess joint motion, muscle strength and endurance, function of heart and lungs, and performance of activities required in daily living, among other responsibilities. Treatment includes therapeutic exercises, cardiovascular endurance training, and training in activities of daily living. (2) A physical therapist is a person qualified by an accredited program in physical therapy, licensed by the state, and practicing within the scope of that license. Physical therapists treat disease, injury, or loss of a bodily part by physical means, such as the application of light, heat, cold, water, electricity, massage and exercise. They develop treatment plans based upon each patient&#39;s strengths, weaknesses, range of motion and ability to function. (3) A health professional who specializes in physical therapy- the health care field concerned primarily with the treatment of disorders with physical agents and methods, such as massage, manipulation, therapeutic exercises, cold, heat (including short-wave, microwave, and ultrasonic diathermy), hydrotherapy, electric stimulation and light to assist in rehabilitating patients and in restoring normal function after an illness or injury."/>
  <compose>
    <include>
      <system value="http://hl7.org/fhir/sid/ca-hc-npn"/>
      <filter>
        <property value="concept"/>
        <op value="is-a"/>
        <value value="225100000N"/>
      </filter>
    </include>
  </compose>
</ValueSet>